A Guide to the Institute of International Education records, Publications, Paper records, RG 3, Series 1 FA1291
Rockefeller Archive Center
Institute of International Education records, Publications, Paper records, RG 3, Series 1
1920-2017
Rockefeller Archive Center
Institute Of International Education, Inc.
FA1291
52.54 Cubic Feet 40 standard record storage boxes
Arrangement
Records remain as received.
Scope and Contents
Contains publications produced by the Institute of International Education (IIE), publications produced by IIE in partnership with others, as well as publications collected by IIE that were produced by other foundations, institutions and government agencies. Contents include: reports, pamphlets, surveys, conference proceedings, policy papers and a selection of IIE Annual Reports. Much of the material is guides for foreign students studying in the United States, U.S. students studying abroad as well as guides for foreign students returning home following the completion of their residencies in the United States. Records may or may not duplicate those found in "Publications, Microforms, RG 3, Series 2" (FA1315).
Biographical / Historical
The Institute of International Education (IIE) was established in 1919 by Nobel Prize winners Nicholas Murray Butler, Elihu Root and Stephen Duggan, Sr. The founders sought greater understanding among nations, primarily through the establishment of international educational exchange between United States institutes of higher education and foreign actors interested in formulating and developing active and ongoing educational understanding. As the Institute grew, developed and matured, it has continued to focus in the area of scholars exchange, as well as education services, international development and leadership training.
IIE initially focused on facilitating student, faculty, and teacher exchanges with European countries. In the 1930s their scope expanded beyond Europe to include exchanges between the Soviet Union and Latin America. During this period the Institute also established the Emergency Committee to Aid Displaced German Scholars which later expanded to include scholars fleeing facist Spain and Italy as well. In the 1950s this program was utilized to support Hungarian refugees. In the early 2000s IIE Trustees together with other donors endowed the Scholar Rescue Fund (SRF).
Following WWII, the Institute helped establish the Association of International Educators (NAFSA) and the Council on International Education Exchange (CIEE) for which they serve to administer the CIEE faculty component and the graduate student component of the Fullbright program, which continues to today as the Institute's largest program.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Records were transferred to RAC by the Institute of International Education through several accessioned in 2017.
Related Materials
The Council for International Exchange of Scholars (CIES) collection is available at the University of Arkansas.
The Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars records are available at the New York Public Library.
The International Fellowship Fund (IFF) Archives are available at Columbia University.
Other Finding Aids
Institute of International Education records are available in the following other finding aids:
Institute of International Education records, Alumni and Historical Files, RG 1 (FA1289)
Institute of International Education records, Fellowship Cards (Grantee Locator Cards), RG 2 (FA1290)
Institute of International Education records, Publications, Microforms, RG 3, Series 2 (FA1315)
Institute of International Education records, Photographic Files, RG 4 (FA1288)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
- News Bulletins of the Institute of International Education, Volume XVI - Volume XXIV, Volume XXVI - Volume XXVIII, 1940-1953 (Box 1)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Eight, No. 3 - The American Universities Union in Europe, 1972 November 1 (Box 2)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Eleven, No. 4 - Eighth Annual Report of the Director, 1930 October 1 (Box 2)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Fourteen, No. 2 - Handbook for American Students in Italy, 1933 January 25; 2 copies (Box 2)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Fourteen, No. 5 - Guide Book for American Students in the British Isles, 1933 November 15; 2 copies (Box 2)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Fifteen, No. 1 - Guide Book for Foreign Students in the United States, 1934 May 15 (Box 2)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Fifteen, No. 2 - Fellowships and Scholarships Open to Foreign Students for Study in the United States, 1934 October 1; 2 copies (Box 2)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Fifteen, No. 3 - Fifteenth Annual Report of the Director, 1934 October 1 (Box 2)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Sixteen, No. 2 - Fellowships and Scholarships Open to American Students for Study in Foreign Countries, 1935 November 1; 6 copies (Box 2)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Seventeen, No. 1 - Directory of American Fellows Studying Under the Auspices of the American German Student Exchange, 1925-1935, 1936 February 1 (Box 2)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Eighteen, No. 1 - Guide Book for Foreign Students in the United States, 1937 March 1; 2 copies (Box 2)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Twenty, No. 1 - Handbook for American Students in France, 1939 July 1 (Box 2)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Twenty-Three, No. 1 - Directory of Former Fellows of the American Field Service Fellowships For French Universities, Inc., 1919-1942, 1942 May 1; 3 copies (Box 2)
- Institute of International Education - Bulletin, Series Twenty-Three, No. 2 - Report of the Conference of Foreign Student Advisors, Cleveland, OH, 1942 April 28-30, 1942 August 1; 2 copies (Box 2)
- Special Report - Conference on International Student Exchanges, University of Michigan, 1948 May 10-12 (Box 2)
- The National Association of Foreign Student Advisors - Report of the Conference on International Educational Exchanges and Annual Meeting, Chicago, IL, 1950 March 22-25 (Box 2)
- A Report to Congress from the U.S. Advisory Commission on International Educational and Cultural Affairs, 1963 (Box 2)
- Lawrence Duggan - IIE Publications, 1978 (Box 2)
- College of University Programs of Academic Exchange, Committee on Educational Interchange Policy, 1960 March (Box 2)
- World Progress through Educational Exchange - The Story of a Conference, 1959 May (Box 2)
- Tribute to Lawrence Duggan, 1948 (Box 2)
- Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Program - "Humphrey Fellows" Publication, 1981-1991, 1999 (Box 2)
- Reports on IIE Seminars in the Soviet Union (Education, the Arts, Industrial Technology and Agriculture), 1959-1960 (Box 2)
- Black Education in South Africa - The Current Situtation, David R. Smock, 1983 January (Box 3, Folder 1)
- African Students: Challenge, Opportunity, Responsibility - Recommendations from The Wingspread Conference, Racine, WI, 1961 December 17-18; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 2)
- IIE Survey of the African Student: His Achievements and His Problems, 1961 November; 4 copies (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Program - "Humphrey Fellows" Publication, 1987-1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Zimman Newsletter, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- World Leadership and International Education, An Address by Hubert H. Humphrey, IIE, New York, 1966 December 6; 4 copies (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Wit and Wisdom of Hubert H. Humphrey (Box 3, Folder 7)
- South Africa Working Papers, 1987-1997 (Box 3, Folder 8-13)
- Handbook on International Study for U.S. Nationals - Study in Europe, 1976; 4 copies (Box 4)
- Handbook on International Study for U.S. Nationals - Study in the American Republics Area, 1976; 5 copies (Box 4)
- US Government Grants, 1950-1956 (Box 4)
- American Education, Henry S. Commager, 1970 (Box 4)
- The American Economy, Henry S. Commager, 1970 (Box 4)
- The American People, Henry S. Commager, 1970 (Box 4)
- American Cultural Traits, Henry S. Commager, 1970 (Box 4)
- American Government, Henry S. Commager, 1970 (Box 4)
- IIE, The Learning Traveler, Vol. 1 - US College-Sponsored Programs Abroad: Academic Year, 3 copies (Box 4)
- IIE - South African Education Program: An Evaluation Report, 1985 November (Box 5, Folder 1)
- IIE - U.S. Independent Sector Involvement in Southern Africa - A Report to the Southern Africa Grantmakers Affinity Group, 3 copies (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Transforming Southern Africa: An Overview of American Support for Southern Africa's Development - A Report to the Sourthern Africa Grantmakers Affinity Group (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Private Sector Involvement in Southern Africa - A Report to the Southern Africa Grantmakers Affinity Group (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Official U.S. Involvement in Southern Africa - A Report to the Southern Africa Grantmakers Affinity Group (Box 5, Folder 5)
- South Africa Working Papers, 1994-1997 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
- Hong Kong Scholarship Program, 1966-1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Diamond Ball - Publicity, 1964, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
- Diamond Ball - Publications, 1969-1975 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
- Council on Higher Education in the American Republics (CHEAR), 1962-1970 (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
- Sponsored Projects, 1975-1985 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
- IIE - US Agency for International Development, 1974-1997 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
- Educational Associates, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Foreign Fulbright Directory of Grantees, 1964-1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Directory of Agencies in New York City Providing Community Services for International Students and Sponsored Visitors, 1962, 1968, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Conferences (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Meet the USA - Handbook for Foreign Students in the United States, 1945-1959 (Box 7, Folder 3-5)
- Meet the USA - Handbook for Foreign Students in the United States - Foreign Translations (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Handbook on International Study for U.S. Nationals, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
- Handbook on International Study: A Guide for Foreign Students on Study in the United States and for U.S. Students on Study Abroad, 1955; 2 copies (Box 8)
- Handbook on International Study: A Guide for Foreign Students on Study in the United States and for U.S. Students on Study Abroad, 1958; 2 copies (Box 8)
- Handbook on International Study: For U.S. Nationals, 1965; 2 copies (Box 8)
- Handbook on International Study for U.S. Nationals, 1971; 2 copies (Box 8)
- Handbook on International Study: For Foreign Nationals, 1961; 2 copies (Box 8)
- Handbook on International Study: For Foreign Nationals, 1965; 2 copies (Box 8)
- Handbook on U.S. Study for Foreign Nationals, 1973 (Box 8)
- IIE Annual Reports, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- IIE Annual Reports, 1960-1965; Hard bound (Box 9, Folder 2)
- IIE Annual Reports, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- IIE Annual Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- IIE Annual Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- IIE Annual Reports, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- IIE Annual Reports, 1975, 1980, 1982-1985, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- IIE Annual Reports, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- IIE Annual Reports, 1996-1999 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- IIE Annual Reports, 2002-2003 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- IIE Annual Reports, 2005-2008 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- A Quarter Century - Board of Foreign Scholarships, 1971; 2 copies (Box 10)
- IIE Guides for Foreign Students, 3 copies (Box 10)
- Higher Education Reform: Implications for Foreign Students, 1978; 2 copies (Box 10)
- The University in Society: An Inter-American Dialogue, 1974; 2 copies (Box 10)
- Report on the Inter-American Group Study Projects for South American Students and Professionals, 1942 December 15 (Box 10)
- Closing Dinner of IIE's 50th Anniversary, 1919-1969, Hotel Domenico, New York City, 1970 April 30 (Box 10)
- The Goals of Student Exchange, 1955 January (Box 10)
- Higher Education in Latin America: Current and Future (ICED), Alphonso Ocampo Lomodo (Box 10)
- La Universidad en la Sociedad, 2 copies (Box 10)
- Guidelines for the Admission and Placement of Students from the Middle East and North Africa, 1966 (Box 10)
- Foreign Study for U.S. Undergraduates - A Survey of College Programs and Policies, 1958 August (Box 10)
- IIE Today (Box 10)
- Workshop on Admission of Foreign Students (sponsored by CEEB and IEB), 1964 (Box 10)
- A Study of the Use of the Cooperative Plan of Education to Implement Closer Ties Between Postsecondary Institutions and Industry in the Arab Countries and Iran, A Report Prepared for the IIE by Asa S. Knowles, Chancellor, Northeastern University, Boston, MA, 1977 September (Box 10)
- The First 75 Years of the Institute of International Education, 1994 (Box 10)
- Publics and Diplomats in the Global Communications Age, 1998 (Box 10)
- World Higher Education Communique Index (Box 10)
- Education: A Global Commitment, International Education: A Global Resource (Box 10)
- This Issue: International Education Trends 2000 (Association of American Colleges), 1979 Summer (Box 10)
- IIE Various Brochures (Box 10)
- A Report to the President of the United States, 1961 January (Box 10)
- The Unofficial Ambassador (The Committee on Friendly Relations Among Foreign Students), 1953 (Box 10)
- IIE Reports (Box 10)
- Academic Orientation for Foreign Graduate Students (A Study of The Economic Institute), 1967 (Box 10)
- The World is Bound by City Streets (Project City Streets), 2 copies (Box 10)
- The Arts and Exchange of Persons, 1956 October 4-5; 2 copies (Box 10)
- The IIE at 50: 1919-1969 - International Education Resources and Responsibilities in the 70s - The Story of a Conference, 2 copies (Box 10)
- World Progress through Educational Exchange - The Story of a Conference, 1959 May; 2 copies (Box 10)
- Guide to Foreign Medical Schools, Daniel Marien, 1973 April; 4 copies (Box 10)
- Undergraduate Study Abroad - U.S. College Sponsored Programs - New Edition, 2 copies (Box 10)
- Undergraduate Study Abroad - U.S. College Sponsored Programs, 1966; 2 copies (Box 10)
- Sponsored Projects, 1986; 2 copies (Box 10)
- Brochures (Box 10)
- Facts and Information About IIE (Box 10)
- International Education of Cultural Exchange, Vol. XI, No. 1, 1975 (Box 10)
- 30 Years with the Fulbright Program, 1977 (Box 11)
- Fulbright at Fifty, 1997 July (Box 11)
- Fulbright Association, The Fullbright Newsletter, Vol. XVII, No. 3, 1995 (Box 11)
- Fulbright Brochures - Fullbright Scholars Program (Box 11)
- Living in the United States: A Handbook for Visiting Fulbright Scholars (Box 11)
- Manual for Fulbright Program Advisors (Box 11)
- The Fulbright Program: A History, Walter Johnson and Francis C. Colligan, 1965 (Box 11)
- The Fulbright Difference, 1948-1992. Edited by Richard T. Ardent and David Lee Rubin, 1993 (Box 11)
- US College and University Policies, Practices and Problems in Admitting Foreign Students, 1965 (Box 11)
- Orientation Notes (Printouts) (Box 11)
- Regional Education Profile: Central America, 1986 September (Box 11)
- IIE 1981 (Box 11)
- ISO 14000 - The American Experience with Environmental Management Systems, 1996 (Box 11)
- US-AEP Environmental Exchange Program, May 15, 1995 - May 15, 1997 (Box 11)
- The Japanese Leaders Program of the Department of the Army - An Evaluation of the Program, 1950-1951, Occasional Paper No. 1, 1952 October (Box 11)
- Exporting Technical Education - A Survey and Case Study of Foreign Professionals with U.S. Graduate Degree, Charles Susskind and Lynn Schell, 1968; 2 copies (Box 11)
- University Government and The Foreign Graduate Student - A Summary of the Colloquim on the Foreign Graduate Student, Held at Wingspread, Racine, WI, 1967 March 30-31, 1969 (Box 11)
- The Foreign Graduate Student: Priorities for Research and Action - A Colloquim Held at Wingspread, Racine, WI, 1970 June 16-17, 1971 (Box 11)
- The Foreign Undergraduate Student: Institutional Priorities for Action - A Colloquim Held at Wingspread, Racine, WI, 1974 June 20-21, 1975 (Box 11)
- The Foreign Student in United States Community and Junior Colleges - A Colloquim Held at Wingspread, Racine, WI, 1977 October 18-20, 1978 (Box 11)
- Regional Education Profile: Asia, 1986 March; 2 copies (Box 11)
- The World Higher Education Communique Special Report: Overseas Educational Development, 1981 - Mexico, South America, Southeast Asia (Box 11)
- News Bulletin, 1951-1952 (Box 11)
- Education Para Graduadas en Ciencias Agropecuarias (Box 11)
- A Beacon of Hope, 1963 April (Box 11)
- A Sequel to A Beacon of Hope, 1964 August (Box 11)
- A Necessary and New Task - The Eleventh Report of the US Advisory Commission on International Educational and Cultural Affairs, 1975 June (Box 11)
- Landmark Events in the History of Cultural Affairs, 1973 (Box 11)
- International Educational Exchange: The Opening Decades, 1946-1966 - A Report of the Board of Foreign Scholarships (Box 11)
- Report of the US Advisory Commission on Pubic Diplomacy, 1982 (Box 11)
- Research of U.S. Students Abroad: Bibliography with Abstracts, Henry D. Weaver, 1989; 2 copies (Box 11)
- International Education Exchange: A Bibliography, Richard E. Spencer and Ruth Awe, 1970s; 2 copies (Box 11)
- The Winter Party - Publicity Book (Box 12, Folder 1)
- The Winter Party, 1970s-1980s; 24 Volumes (Box 12, Folder 2-6)
- The Winter Party - Publicity, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Overseas: The Magazine of Educational Exchange, 1962-1964; 5 Volumes (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Study Down Under - Magazine for Study in Australia, 2002-2003; 4 Volumes (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Overseas: The Magazine of Educational Exchange, Vol. 1, 1961-1962; 2 copies (Box 12)
- Overseas: The Magazine of Educational Exchange Vol. 3, 1963-1964; 2 copies (Box 12)
- Institute of International Education, Institute Bulletins, 1920-1945; 10 Volumes (Box 13)
- Issues in International Education, No. 1-8 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- The Population Involved in International Education: Digest, Summer 1997 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- World Higher Education Communique, 1979-1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Foreign Fulbright Fellows - Directory of Students, 1993-1994; 2 copies (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Directory of American Fulbright Scholars, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Fulbright 40th Report, 2003-2004 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Fulbright Scholar Program - Grants for U.S. Faculty and Professionals, 1998-1999; 2 copies (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Fulbright U.S. Student Program - Fulbright and Related Grants for Graduate Study and Research Abroad, 1997-1998, 1998-1999; 2 copies (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Fulbright Grants for Faculty and Professionals - Application Booklet, 1996-1997 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Fulbright and Related Grants for Graduate Study and Research Abroad, 1996-1997 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Fulbright Application for Grants, 1997-2000 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- U.S. Student Fulbright Grants and other Grants for Graduate Study and Research Abroard, 1995-1996; 2 copies (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Fulbright-Hays Student Exchange Program Seminar, Wingspread Conference, Racine, WI, 1967 September 20-22 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Board of Foreign Scholarships - Fulbright Program Exchanges, 1979-1985 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Board of Foreign Scholarships - Reports on Exchanges, 1972-1978; 7 volumes (Box 14, Folder 15)
- The Fulbright Program, 1988-1990; 3 Volumes (Box 14, Folder 16)
- U.S. College-Sponsored Programs Abroad, Academic Year, 1973-1983; 2 copies each of 10 Volumes. (Box 15, Folder 1-5)
- International Investment in Human Capital - Overseas Education for Development, Editor, Crawford D. Goodwin (IIE Research Report 24) (Box 15, Folder 6)
- IIE Reports and Other Reports, 1966-1979 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Curriculum: U.S. Capacities, Developing Countries' Needs: A Report from the 1979 Conference on International Education, International Education: The Global Context, the U.S. Role - A Cooperative Examination of Critical Issues, Washington, D.C., Richard B. Myer, Session Chairman, 1979 February 26-18; 2 copies (Box 15, Folder 8)
- A Survey of Policy Changes: Foreign Students in Public Institutions of Higher Education (IIE Research Report 3 and 8), 1982-1986; 2 Volumes (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Education for International Responsibilities: A Status Report on International Exchange of Persons, 1956-1957, Second National Conference on Exchange of Persons, 1956 December 5-6; 2 Copies (Box 15, Folder 10)
- IIE Reports Volume 1-6 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Various CEIP-Publications (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Meet the USA, Henry Steele Commager, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Educational Associate Newsletter, 1992 February-March; 2 copies (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Investing in People - The First 75 Years of the Institute of International Education, 1919-1994, 3 copies (Box 16, Folder 4)
- IIE at 50 - Institute of International Education, 1919-1969 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- IIE 1981 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- IIE Annual Report 1996 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Raising the Curtain - A Report with Recommendations on Academic Exchanges with East Central Europe and the USSR, Barbara B. Burn (East Central Europe Information Exchange Report 1), 1991; 2 copies (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Continental Responsibility: European and International Support for Higher Education and Research in East Central Europe, Editors, Mary E. Kirk and Aaron A. Rhodes, 1994; 2 copies (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Various CEIP-Publications (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Committee on Educational Interchange Policy - Meetings - Minutes, 1958-1964 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Committee on Educational Interchange Policy - Meetings, 1960-1964 (Box 16, Folder 12-16)
- Overseas: The Magazine of Educational Exchange, Vol. 2, 1962-1963 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- IIE Research Reports No. 11-14, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- IIE Research Reports No. 15-18, 1988-1989 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- IIE Research Reports No. 19-24, 1989-1993 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- IIE Research Reports No. 25-27, 1993-1996 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- IIE Research Reports No. 28-29, 1997-1999 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Committee on Educational Interchange Policy, 1958-1964 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- IIE Updates-Study Abroad, 1974 December - 1978 December (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Fulbright Evaluation Research Report, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Guides - Fields of Study Handbook for Countries Participating in the Buenos Aires Covention and Fullbright Programs, U.S. Student Department, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Guides - Undergraduate Study in the United States: The Four Year College - A Guide for Foreign Students, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Guides - Teacher Preparation Institutions in the United States - A Guide for Foreign Students, 1962 September (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Guides - Teacher Education in the United States - A Guide for Foreign Students, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Guides - Admission to American Colleges and Universities: Advice from IIE to the Hong Kong Applicant (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Guides - Study of Agriculture in the U.S. - A Guide for Foreign Students, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Guides - Study in U.S. Colleges and Universities and Other Studies (Box 18, Folder 10)
- The International Migration of High-Level Manpower (The Committee on International Migration of Talent), 1970; 2 Copies (Box 18)